FIONA MURRAY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER



929-344-2807



fionam.dev@gmail.com



Queens, NY



https://github.com/lavenderfi

Enthusiastic full-stack software developer, eager to keep expanding upon current knowledge. Hopeful to emphasize the important of accessibility and diversity, and how it comes into play when developing applications that are aware of all of its potential user-base.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

- JavaScript
- Problem-Solving
- Back-end
- Teamwork / Communication
- development Front End
- Adaptability
- development
- Persistence
- Computer Literacy

PROJECTS

Every Daisy of the Week

Worked with a team to create an online ecommerce full-stack application from scratch. Features include a fully functioning cart that users can add and remove items from, and checkout and payment functionality with the Stripe API. It was built using a PostgreSQL database that was called upon with Express. The front end was managed through React, with Redux to manage the state.

Webby

• The capstone project for the Grace Hopper Program, worked within a team to build a social media application from the ground up, with the goal of connecting users through hobbies. This project includes a fully functional group chat feature, as well as an interactive network graph that connects the user with others through their interests. The database and authentication are managed through Firebase, with React and Redux on the front end.

EDUCATION

FULLSTACK ACADEMY - Grace Hopper Program, Full-time May-September 2022

- Worked diligently to learn and expand upon previous knowledge of JavaScript, as well as various new technologies to be able to work on every part of the stack. These technologies include:
 - JavaScript, React, Redux, Express, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Git
- Developed multiple functional full-stack applications, including a single-page, online shopping application, various simple projects such as a simple music player, as well as a finished capstone project, done in 3 weeks.

HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY - Psychology BA 2016-2020

- Graduated with a 3.5 GPA, with additional minors in LGBT+ Studies and Religion
- Attended trainings on gender and sexuality, as well as being a mentor to younger LGBT+ students, helping them adapt to their new environment through the lens of diversity and inclusion.
- Worked with a team to organize multiple events to inform and help fellow classmates be more open and aware of the diversity around them.

EXPERIENCE

RETAILMERCHANDISER - Stew Leonard's 2019-2021

- Assisted customers on the floor and on the phone by answering questions and completing special requests.
- Packaged food and filled up/organized sales floor, prepared food and prepared sales floor for the following day.
- Demoed specific foods for customers to boost sales.

SALES ASSOCIATE - Hot Topic Inc.

2021-2022

- Assisted and greeted customers, helped customers find relevant products based on their interests and needs
- Operated cash register, signed up customers for loyalty program and provided enthusiastic customer service.
- Organized and cleaned sales floor, set up merchandise to be put out.